Guide to the Joseph Fowler Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Joseph Fowler papers
1813-1830
MS 1278
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.25
Correspondence, documents, lecture notes, and other papers of Joseph Fowler, student at Yale University in the Class of 1817.
Fowler, Joseph, 1798-1825
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the papers of Joseph Fowler, a student at Yale College in the class of 1817. In addition to a small amount of correspondence with family members and others, there is a notebook made up of drafts of letters, a partial diary, notes taken during lectures by Professor James L. Kingsley, and other papers, all stitched together. Also included in the Papers are a few receipts and other financial papers, a program from Fowler's Yale commencement in 1817, his Yale B.A. and M.A. diplomas and several other certificates, loose notes and a second notebook containing lecture notes.
Biographical / Historical
Joseph Fowler was the eldest child of Joseph and Abigail (Baldwin) Fowler, of Milford, Connecticut. He was born on October 7, 1798. He graduated from Yale College in 1817 and continued to receive a master's degree. He died in Milford in 1825 and was never married.
Fowler, Joseph, 1798-1825; Kingsley, James Luce, 1778-1852; Yale College (1718-1887). Class of 1817; Yale University -- Students
- Inventory
  - Correspondence, 1815-1820 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1821, 1830 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, including lectures by Prof. James L. Kingsley, a portion of a diary, drafts of letters, notes, and other loose notes, Circa 1813-1820 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Notebook, "Dr. Dwight's Remarks...", Circa 1816-1823 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Financial papers, 1814-1823 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Certificates and diplomas, 1817-1820 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    General note
    See also: Inventory Box 2
  - "Scheme of the Exercises at the Public Commencement of Yale College", 1817 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Biographic notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Certificates and diplomas, undated (Box 2)